萌月&諸神字幕組
目覚めては繰り返す
Day after day, I awake in a daze,
mezamete ha kurikaesu nemui asa ha
目覚めては繰り返す　眠い朝は
眠い朝は
襟のタイをきつく締め
And fasten my collar tightly.
eri no tai wo kitsuku shime
襟のタイをきつく締め
教室のドアくぐると
As I walk through the door to my classroom,
kyoushitsu no doa kuguru to hon no sukoshi
教室のドアくぐるとほんの少し
ほんの少し胸を張って歩き出せる
I have the slightest bit of pride.
mune wo hatte arukidaseru
胸を張って歩き出せる
Then a wind rushed through that normal, everyday life.
sonna nichijou ni fukinukeru kaze
そんな日常に吹き抜ける風
そんな日常に
吹き抜ける風
聞こえた気がした　感じた気がしたんだ
I have a feeling I can hear it,
kikoeta ki ga shita
聞こえた気がした
I have a feeling I can sense it,
kanjita ki ga shitanda
感じた気がしたんだ
震えだす 今この胸で
Beginning to tremble within my chest.
furuedasu ima kono mune de
震え出す今この胸で
I have a feeling it's on its way,
mou kuru ki ga shita
もう来る気がした
As the millions of stars began to disappear,
ikuoku no hoshi ga kiesatteku no wo
幾億の星が消え去ってくのを
I sent them on their way,
miokutta
見送った
見送った 手を振った
Waving my hand,
te wo futta
手を振った
良かったねと
Whispering, "Congratulations".
yokatta ne, to
よかったね、と
1st Introspection Room
Wow, we're finally free.
かぁー やっと解放された
My neck's all stiff from sleeping on that hard floor.
Oh, that's good, mate.
あんなかってぇ床で寝かされて首いったー
I thought this school was supposed to become our paradise if we tarnished Tenshi's name.
天使を失墜させればワタシたちの楽園となるんじゃなかったんですか
この学校は
Why aren't you wearing anything?
なんで脱いでるの
What's wrong with that guy...?
なんなんだ　あの連中
Breezeway
Below First Bridge
Next time they come, we'll have our retribution against them, as well as Tenshi.
今度来たら天使同様　返り討ちにしてくれる
They're NPCs, so you can't.
一般生徒だからダメよ
にしても　変ね
Still, this is strange.
What is?
なにがだ
There were no NPCs before that would force us to reflect on our actions.
ワタシたちにこんな形で反省を強いる一般生徒なんていなかった
Maybe Tenshi was acting as a deterrent.
天使が抑止力になってたんじゃないのか
That's possible.
そうね
The NPCs are basically there to be an
example for what we should be doing,
NPCの行いは基本的にはアタシたちのなすべき模範だけど
but their emotions are the same as actual humans.
その感情は現実の人間と同じもの
It's not any real surprise to find a cranky one amongst them.
どんな偏屈なやつがいたって
不思議じゃないってワケか
So there are NPCs that go above and beyond, too.
つまりは　行き過ぎたやつもいるってことだな～
Such as that deputy student council president...
それが生徒会長代理
返り討ちができない分　天使よりヤッカイだぜ
He's more of a pain than Tenshi since we can't fight back.
What do we do, Yurippe?
どうする　ゆりッペ
色仕掛けいきますか
How about sex appeal?
And where exactly are you hiding that?
お前のどこに色気があるんだよ
What did you say?! Have you ever seen me nude?
んだと　見たことあんのか
翻譯夏矢今瘋
臺本眯眯 奔奔
I can imagine too much already with your clothes on.
上着越しでも十分わかる
You ever touched them?!
けッ　揉んだことあんのか　コラァ
They have just the perfect softness, don't they?!
絶妙な柔らかさなんじゃーい！
特效 saber 時間&後期 月染不透
校對　矢今瘋小夜子
How should I know?!
知るかよ
How unwise.
あさはかなり
萌月諸神聯合譯製
So, what will our activities from here on be?
で　これからの活動はどうしますか
Anti-Tenshi Operation HQ
I see you finally put your shirt on.
ようやく来たか
We'll take a few actions as tests.
試しにちょっと動いてみましょう
とりあえず　それぞれ好き勝手に授業を受けてみて
Attend class and make trouble as you'd like for now.
あ　一般生徒の邪魔はあんまりしないように
Oh, but don't bother the NPCs too much.
以上　解散
That's all. Dismissed.
よし
Otonashi-kun.
音無君
うん？
You hold on to this.
これ　あんたもってきなさい
I thought that was valuable here.
それ　ここでは貴重なものなんじゃッ
なぜ　オレなんかに
Why are you giving it to me?
いいから
Just take it.
Tenshi won't be acting against us any more.
天使はもう動かない
昨夜　それは証明できた
We were able to prove that last night.
The remaining problem is the deputy president.
残る問題は生徒会長代理
かく乱しまくったら　どう動く
What sort of obstacles will he be coming up with?
Classroom
Classroom Building A
This is so exciting.
すごいドキドキする
Eating a snack in the middle of class!
授業中にお菓子を食べるなんて
I ate it! I just ate one!
食べた
いま食べた
I'm eating a snack in the middle of class!
ボク授業中に堂々とお菓子食べちゃってる
I'm so bold!
なんて思い切ったことしちゃってるんだ
Reach if this goes through.
通れば　お入り
Sorry. Reach, Pairs.
Ouch. Are you serious?
残念　リーチ　チートイ
Dora dora. Dealer Mangan.
ドラドラ親満
What the heck?! Hisako's the only one above 30,000 points...
なんだよ　くそ　久子のひとり浮きじゃねえか
Ah... just wild heaven.
How could we lose to a girl...?
女相手に何たる体たらくだ
You guys, keep it down a little more.
そこの一角　もう少し静かに
Oh, our bad.
あ～　すみません
Teacher! Bathroom, please!
先生　トイレ
You again... Go ahead.
またお前か
行ってこい
What is she doing?
あいつはなにをしてるんだ
Playing the role of a student that goes to the
bathroom every other minute. What a dumbass.
一分おきにトイレに行く生徒だとさ
阿呆だな
What are we going to do?
オレたちはどうする
We'll just chat some, like this.
こうやってだべってりゃいいさ
Hey, check that out.
にしても　異様だな
Teacher! Bathroom, please!
先生　トイレ
Go ahead.
はい　行ってこい
A dumbass.
阿呆だ
That's enough, you lot.
そこまでだ　キサマら
Here comes Naoi Ayato-sama.
来たぜ　直井文人さま
I need to use the bathroom!
ワタシ　トイレですから
Crap! Beat it, guys!
ヤベエ　失せるぜ
I'll be back.
I'll be back
What do you think you're doing?
キサマ　なんのつもりだ
Seems he can't hear me.
聞こえてないようだ
Fine by me. Take him to the Introspection Room just like this.
いいだろ～　このまま反省室へ運べ
What are you telling me to reflect on?!
なにを反省しろっていうのだ
授業中に堂々と眠り
How can you ask such a question...
...while sleeping in the middle of the class and intimidating an innocent student?
あまつさえ　罪なき一般生徒を恫喝しておいて
よくそんな疑問が抱けますね
Your ignorance is praiseworthy.
ある意味天晴れです
What was that?!
んだと
くそ　待って　逃げるのか
Hey, hang on! Why should we run away?!
I'm right here! Bring it on!
おい　俺はここだ　かかって来い　おい　お前ら
Hey, where are you taking me?
Is there any point in doing this?
こんなこと続けて意味あんのか
Rear Side
School Cafeteria  3rd Floor
Let's see...
Hey, are you hungry at all?
あのさ　腹へってないか
I'm not. Not at this kind of hour.
減ってないけど
こんな中途半端な時間に
I see.
そうか
At the cafeteria, there's some mapo doufu
famous for being so hot that no one can eat it.
学食にさ　辛すぎて誰も手を出さないって
ウワサのマーボー豆腐があってさ
I gave it a try and found out it was surprisingly good.
ためしに食ってみたら　驚くほどうまくてさ
Well, so... If you're interested, I'll treat you.
あのさ
よかったらおごるよ
どう　かな
What... do you say?
Why are you still sitting?
なにしてるの
O-Oh, yeah. Coming!
おお　行くよ
School Cafeteria  Interior
The appearance really is deadly...
やっぱ　見た目スゲーな～
相変わらず　カラッ
I knew it was hot!
I heard most people eat this with rice.
普通はご飯と一緒に食べるとか聞いたんだけど
I see.
そう
You don't find this too hot?
そうってこれじゃ辛過ぎない
It's fine. Only...
別に　ただ
"Only..."?
ただ
It's delicious.
うまいわ
I get it.
そっか
It isn't so much that you like the spicy flavour, it's that mapo doufu's your favourite meal.
辛いのは好きっちより
マーボー豆腐が好物なんだな
どうした
What's wrong?
So I like mapo doufu?
ワタシマーボー豆腐が好きなの
I mean, don't ask me.
イヤ　そんなオレに聞かれても
That's the first time I've thought of it that way.
初めて知った
Tachibana-san.
タチバナさん
What are you doing at this hour?
こんな時間に何をしてるんですか
Can't you tell? We're eating.
見りゃわかるだろ
食事だ
Eating food during break time is against the school code.
休み時間の食事は校則違反だ
忘れてた
I'd forgotten.
You're right. It is against the school code.
そうだったわね
校則違反だった
忘れてた
I had forgotten that.
I can tell that she honestly had forgotten about it.
こいつ　素で忘れてたにちがいない
Her favourite food of mapo doufu really is scary...
好物のマーボー豆腐恐るべし
Take them away.
連れて行け
Damn it!
くそ
You shouldn't lock us up just for eating mapo doufu during break time!
休み時間に　マーボー豆腐食ったからって
これはないだろ
Besides, where are we?
つーか　どこだよここは
This is like a prison.
まるで独房じゃないか
I'm sleepy. I'm taking a nap.
眠い
眠るわ
H-Hey, this isn't the time for that!
おいおい　そんな場合かよ
Is there anything else to do?
他になにかすることあるの
Don't you think it's odd that we were shut in such a prison-like place?
おかしいじゃないか
こんな独房みたいなところに閉じ込められてよ
It counts as reflecting upon our actions, so it's fine.
それで反省になるのだから　仕方ないじゃない
Even then! Who would take a nap in this situation?
イヤ　だからってこの状況で寝るか　普通
おやすみなさい
Good night.
She's seriously sleeping...
マジで寝やがった
モエのつきカミガミ
何の音だ
What was that noise? An earthquake?
地震？
戦闘？　助けか
Is there a battle? A rescue operation?
そうだ　これあった
Oh yeah!
I had this on me!
ゆり　閉じこめられた
Yuri! We've been locked up!
壊れてる
It's broken.
ガラクタ押し付けやがって
Giving me a piece of junk like that!
音無君　音無君
-nashi-kun?
Otonashi-kun?
聞こえる
Can you hear me? Otonashi-kun?
音無君
聞こえるぞ
I hear you!
これを聞いてると信じて話すわ
I'll continue speaking assuming that you can hear me.
音無君
Otonashi-kun, listen carefully.
よく聞いて
直井文人はNPCじゃなかったの
Naoi Ayato wasn't an NPC.
ヒトの魂を持った
He's a human with a soul, just like us.
アタシたちと同じ　人間だったの
そんなばかな
No way.
おかしいと思わない?
Don't you find that strange?
もとは副会長
He's been acting as the vice president,
so he's been behaving like a role model student.
模範的な行動を取っていたはずよ
なら　存在を保っていられず消えてなくなるはず
As a result, he should have disappeared
without being able to maintain his existence here.
でも陰湿にね
But in reality he was being insidious,
committing violence against NPCs in the background.
カゲで一般生徒に暴力を振るっていたの
おもてで模範的な活動をし
He acted as a role model before others, but then inflicted violence where he couldn't be seen.
暗で悪事を働く
それでこの世界でのバランスを取っていたというワケ
That's how he maintained the balance to stay in this world.
そんなことを知って何を…
What good does that do?
抑止力だった天使が失脚したことにより
With the deterrent, Tenshi, losing her position, he gained freedom here.
カレはこの世界で自由を手に入れた
まだ目的はわからないけどね
We still don't know what he wants.
On this side, a battle has erupted.
こちらでは戦いが始まってる
あなたが見たこともない
A horrifying scene like you've never witnessed before.
ひどい戦いよ
彼はアタシたちが一般生徒を攻撃できないことも知ってる
He knows that we can't hurt the NPCs.
だから　カレらを盾にも人質にもするのよ
That's why he's using them as shields or even taking them hostage.
アタシたちは言いなりになるしかない
We have no choice but to obey him.
それはもう
It's a one-sided massacre.
一方的な暴力
次々と仲間がやられていってるわ
Our guys are getting killed off one after another.
アタシね　天使は幽閉されてると思うの
I think Tenshi's locked up somewhere.
I searched for her at the Introspection Room we were taken to, but I couldn't find her.
アタシたちが入った反省室を探したわ
げと　見つけられなかった
I believe she's being kept some place that's harder to find.
もっと簡単に抜け出せないような場所に閉じ込められてると思う
ね　音無君　アタシは思うの
Look, Otonashi-kun, I have this hunch.
Aren't you with Tenshi right now?
アナタいま天使と一緒にいるんじゃないかって
ね　音無君
Look, Otonashi-kun... bring Tenshi to us.
天使を連れてきて
To end this horrifying battle, we need Tenshi.
このひどい戦いを終わらせるには
天使の存在が必要なの
時間がないわ　グランドへ来て
We're out of time.
Get out here on the field.
I'm going out now, too. And... well, good luck.
アタシもこれから出る
じゃ　健闘を祈るわ
Damn it! Why am I stuck in a place like this?
くそ
なんたってオレはこんなところに
Wake up, Tachibana!
起きろ　タチバナ
助けてくれ
Help! My friends are in trouble!
仲間が大変なんだ
おかしなことを言うのね
What a strange thing to ask.
助けてほしいのはこっちじゃない
We're the ones who need help.
Yeah, I know that.
ああ～　それは重々承知だ
But you might be able to get us out of here!
でも　お前なら出来るかもしれない
I'm begging you!
頼む
みんなが待ってるんだ
Everyone's waiting!
ガードスキル「ハンドソニク」
Guard Skill: Hand Sonic.
Can you take the door down with that?
それで　あの扉がなんとかなるのか
Doesn't look like it...
ダメか
I didn't create this with the intention of attacking something.
だって攻撃目的には作っていないから
It's only for self-defence.
所詮は自衛用だもの
"Self-defence"?
自衛？
作っていない…
"Didn't create this for"...
I get it!
そうか
最初に会った時のことを覚えてるか
Remember the first time we met?
心臓ぶっさされて死にかけたよな
You stabbed me through the heart and I nearly died.
あなたがおかしなことをいうからよ
Only because you asked such a strange thing.
Yeah. But due to that, I mistook you to be an enemy.
あ　でもあれでお前を敵だと勘違いしちまった
俺には記憶がないんだ
I don't have any memories.
だからお前と戦う理由も実はないんだ
So I actually have no reason to fight against you.
もし俺に記憶があったら
If I'd had my memories...
もしも　最初に馬鹿な質問をしなかったら
If I hadn't asked that stupid question in the beginning,
この世界で俺は　お前の味方でいたかもな
I might have been on your side.
そんな人はいなかったわ
There's no one like that.
いてもいいじゃないか
Well, there can be one, right?
There isn't one. Even if there were, they'd disappear.
いないわ
いたとしても　みんな消えちゃうもの
I see.
おっ　そっか
こいつの味方をするということは
Being on her side means to have an
enjoyable school life and eventually to leave her.
楽しい学園生活送って
この世界から消えてしまうということ　なのか
あっ　あはは　そっか
I get it now. This is laughable.
なんか笑えてくる
How horrible... I feel so sorry for her.
こいつが可哀そう過ぎて　不憫すぎて
なんて世界のシステムだ
What a crazy system this world has.
「ハンドソッ二ク」バージョン２
Hand Sonic: Version 2.
This is designed thinner to improve speed.
高速戦に特化した薄いフォルム
Version 3.
バージョン３
無粋ね
This one is crude.
格好いいじゃん
That's cool, though.
でも　これでも扉は開かないわ
But this won't open the door, either.
ほかにはないのか
You don't have anything else?
I do. Version 4.
あるわ
バージョン４
花の形にしてみたんだけど
I made it look like a flower.
はたしてこれはかわいいかしら
Do you find it cute, I wonder?
Actually, it looks deadly, but...
いやあ　相当禍々しいけど
いけるかもしれない
This might work.
There's something I want you to try.
ひとつ　試してみてほしいんだ
Hand Sonic: Version 2.
「ハンドソッ二ク」バージョン４
バージョン３
Version 3.
バージョン４
Version 4.
It's working!
いける
急ごう
Let's hurry.
What... is this?
なんだ　これ
Hinata!
日向
大丈夫か　日向
Are you all right, Hinata?!
To come running to me first...
真っ先俺に駆け寄ってくるなんて
これなのか
You're into that?
冗談言ってる場合かよ
This isn't the time to joke around!
あそこからどうやって出てきた
How did you get out of there?
扉を壊した
I broke the door.
丹念かけて作ったと思ってるんだ
How many years do you think it took me to make that place?
生徒会長代理として命じる
I order you as the deputy Student Council President.
大人しく戻れ
Return to the room at once.
Tachibana. You see what's going on here.
立花　この惨状だ
それが正しくないってことはわかるよな
You know this isn't the right thing to do, don't you?
「ハンドソニック」
Hand Sonic.
You dare to rebel? Against God?
逆らうのか　神を
僕が神だ
I am God.
Is he completely daft?
馬鹿かこいつ
Yeah, after doing all of this...
こんなにまでしておいて
How foolish.
愚かだ
ここは神を選ぶ世界だと　誰も気付いていないのか
No one has yet to realise that this world exists to choose who is God?
生きていた記憶がある
It's required that your past memories be horrible to come here.
皆一様に酷い人生だったろ
なぜ
Why?
それこそが神になる権利だからだ
Because that's the ticket to becoming God.
生きる苦しみを知る僕らこそが神になる権利を持っているからだ
We, who have known true pain in life, are the only ones who have the right to become God.
僕は今　そこにたどり着けた
I've reached the finish line.
神になって　どうするんだ
What are you going to do, having become God?
安らぎを与える
Give peace.
To us?!
俺達にかよ
無茶苦茶してくれてんじゃねえかよ
Don't be freaking ridiculous!
It's because they resisted.
抵抗するからだ
While you all have souls that have earned the right to become God,
君たちは神になる権利を得た魂であると同時に
生前の記憶に苦しみ　もがき続ける者たちだ
you also suffer the pain of the memories from when you were alive.
God has been chosen.
神は決まった
なら僕はお前たちに安らぎ与えよう
So I will give you all peace.
ゆり
Yuri!
What more are you going to do?!
これ以上なにをする気だ
What... do you want?
な　によ
君は今から成仏するんだ
You'll be resting in peace in a bit.
Do you remember Iwasawa Asami?
岩沢雅美を覚えてるだろう
生前彼女は声を失い
When she was alive, she lost her voice and gave up on her dream to sing.
歌う夢を断念
ひどい家庭環境のもと
Due to her poor family, the end of her life was a sad one.
惨めに死に至った
だが　彼女はこの世界で夢を叶えたんだ
But here in this world, she made her dream a reality.
だから消えた
That's why she disappeared.
成仏できたんだ
She was able to rest in peace.
You will be resting in peace soon, too, together with a happy memory.
貴様も今から成仏するんだ
幸せな夢とともに
You don't know my past!
あなたは私の過去を知らない
知らなくても可能なんだ
It's possible even if I don't know it.
I didn't just prepare Tenshi's prison over such a long period of time.
僕が時間をかけて準備してきたのは
天使の牢獄を作ることだけじゃない
I also practised hypnosis.
催眠術だ
さあ　目を閉じるんだ
Now, close your eyes.
You will now have a happy dream.
貴様は今から幸せな夢を見る
こんな世界でも幸せな夢を見れるんだよ
You can have a happy dream even in a world like this.
まさか　まさか　まさか
This can't be... This just can't... It can't be...
そんな
There's no way...!
あ　あの子たちだ
It's them...
No. This isn't real.
違う　嘘だ
Don't show me those happy faces...
そんな幸せそうな顔しないで
アタシは守れなかったのよ
I couldn't protect you all.
一人ずつ死なせてしまったのよ
I let you three die, one by one.
一人ずつ　一人ずつ
One by one...
そして誰も残らなかった
...and none of you survived!
なのに
Yet...
You know, I'm glad you were our sister.
あのね　お姉ちゃんがお姉ちゃんでよかった
そんな　そんな
Don't...
Don't say that!
止めろーッ
Stop it!
そんな紛いもんの記憶で消すな
Don't erase her with a fake memory!
The lives we spent were real!
俺達の生きてきた人生は本物だ
何一つ嘘もない人生なんだよ
They were all the real deal!
みんな懸命に生きてきたんだよ
Everyone lived the best they could!
そうして刻まれてきた記憶なんだ
That's how our memories were made!
必死に生きてきた記憶なんだ
They're memories from our lives.
それがどんなものであろうが
No matter what they are, it's the life we walked!
俺達の生きてきた人生なんだよ
And you want to be the one to finish painting the picture?
それを結果だけ上塗りしようだなんて
お前の人生だって本物だったはずだろう
Your life should have been the real deal, too!
兄が死んだ
My brother died.
陶芸の名手の家に生まれてしまった
My twin brother and I were born as children of a prestigious potter.
Naoi
僕と双子の兄
兄は幼くして才覚を発揮し
My brother showed talent from when he was little,
後継ぎとして名を世間に知らしめていた
and they sold his name to the world as the heir.
I, on the other hand, would be locked up in a room to play.
僕はと言えば　一人部屋にこもって遊ぶ毎日だった
親からも誰からも期待されない
It was a meaningless life, where no hope was ever placed on me, not even by my parents.
意味のない人生
死んだのはお前だ
The sky was telling me, "You're the one who died."
そう空は告げていた
そう　生きてる僕は兄なのだ
That's right... the one who lived was my brother.
僕は兄とすり替わった
And so I swapped places with my brother.
死んだのは僕ということになった
The world would treat me as the one who'd actually died.
そして　意味のある人生が始まった
And so my life of purpose began.
怪我の治療ということで世間から離れ
As rehabilitation from the injury, I was secluded from society.
リハビリというなのに　厳しい修行が続く
The strict training they called "rehabilitation" lasted forever.
恥を知れ
Shame on you!
父の怒声を聞く毎日
All I ever heard was my father's yelling, every day.
How dare you make something like this?!
こんなもの　作ってきおって
修行は苛烈を極めた
The training was intense.
なんで遠いところに行ったんだ　僕の兄は
My brother had stood on a pedestal so much higher up than me.
But I continued to fight in order to
change my life into a meaningful one.
でも僕は　僕の人生を意味あるものに変えるために挑み続けるんだ
もう　一人で遊ぶ毎日なんて　勿体無い
I wouldn't return to the old days, forced to play alone.
展覧会で入賞を果たした
I won a prize in a show.
兄としては全然ダメな結果だっだろけど
I didn't do nearly as well as my brother could have,
僕としては　今出せる最高の成果だ
but it was the best I could do at my level.
なんだ　お前泣いているのか
What? Are you crying?
馬鹿な
Don't be ridiculous.
だな
You said it. This is ridiculous.
馬鹿な話だ
わしに恥をかかすな
Don't shame me like this.
まったく　何たる結果だ
Honestly. This kind of result is unacceptable.
That was wonderful.
よかった
厳しい父について　これからも修行を続けていこう
I would follow my strict father and continue training.
そして　日本一の陶芸家になろう
And I would become Japan's best potter!
Kento
Then, my father became bedridden.
その父が床に伏せた
回復の見込みはないらしい
The doctor said there was no chance of him getting better.
もう轆轤は回せない
He couldn't spin the wheel any more.
僕に陶芸を教えることはもちろん
He also couldn't teach the art to me any longer,
僕を叱ることもなくなった
and he wouldn't yell at me, either.
食事を与えると　優しげに微笑むのだった
When I fed him, he would kindly smile.
僕の人生の意味は
What is my purpose in life?
こんな腕じゃ工房は持てないし
With my skills, I can't have my own studio, nor can I sustain myself.
独り立ちもできない
ずっとこのひとの世話をしていく人生なのは
Will I take care of him for the rest of my life?
ね　神様
Answer me, God!
"You're the one who died."
あの時死んだのは本当に僕だったよ
I realised the one who'd died that day really was me.
The one who'd worked hard from then on was my brother.
あそこから頑張ったのはずっと兄で
ここにいるのも兄で
It was my brother who was in this room, too.
父と兄しかいなかったんだ
It was him and Father.
僕の人生は偽りだった
My life was all just a fake.
I never existed.
僕はどこにもいなかったんだ
お前の人生だって本物だったはずだろう
Your life should have been the real deal, too!
頑張ったのはお前だ
You're the one who worked hard!
必死にもがいたのもお前だ
You're the one who fought! Isn't that right?!
違うか
何を知った風な
Who do you think you are?
わかるさ
I can tell.
ここにお前もいるんだから
Since you're right here.
なら　あんた認めてくれるの
Then, will you accept it?
このぼくを
That I'm me?
Who else other than you could I possibly be accepting right now?
お前以外のなにを認めろってんだよ
俺が抱いてるのはお前だ
The one in my arms is you.
お前以外いない
There's no one besides you.
お前だけだよ
It's only you.
取ったってどうせ渋柿だぞ
Even if you get it, it's a sour persimmon.
I got it! I got it over Nii-san!
やった　兄さんに勝った
渋柿ごときでなにを
What are you getting worked up over a sour persimmon for?
Still, you're not half-bad, Ayato.
だが　文人もやりおる
一番聞きたかった言葉
Those are the words I wanted to hear most.
僕を認めてくれた言葉
The words of acceptance.
Ayato
●
いつも一人で歩いてた
I've always walked this path alone; when I look back, everyone is so far away.
itsumo hitori de aruiteta furikaeru to minna ha tooku
いつもひとりで歩いてた　振り返るとみんなは遠く
．
●
振り返るとみんなは遠く
それでも私は歩いたそれが強さだった
Even so, I kept on walking. That was my strength.
soredemo atashi ha aruita sore ga tsuyosa datta
それでもあたしは歩いた　それが強さだった
．
もう何も 怖くない
"Nothing frightens me any longer", I mumble softly.
mou nanimo kowakunai sou tsubuyaitemiseru
もう何も恐くない　そう呟いてみせる
．
そうつぶやいてみせる
いつか　人は一人になって
Eventually, everyone ends up alone,
itsuka hito ha hitori ni natte
いつか人は一人になって
思い出の中に生きてくだけ
And is left with only their memories.
omoide no naka ni ikiteku dake
思い出の中に生きてくだけ
孤独さえ愛し笑ってられるように
In order to appreciate even sorrow and continue smiling,
kodoku sae aishi waratterareru you ni
孤独さえ愛し笑ってられるように
私は戦うんだ
I'll keep on fighting,
atashi ha tatakaunda
あたしは戦うんだ
涙なんて見せないんだ
I won't show you my tears.
namida nante misenainda
涙なんて見せないんだ
Next Episode Preview
Monster Stream.
It's finally here!
Just how big is it?
It's a carnival of despair.
Want to do Tornado?
God never falls.
Pull!
In other words, a dumbass.
Overdrive is passive.
I don't want you to underestimate my skills.
You should be able to regain the memory you lost.
Please don't lose sight of yourself.
Thank you, Onii-chan.
This just isn't right... I can't die off like this...